{
    "name": "Chief Minister & The state legislature",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Which is the Upper Chamber of State Legislature in India?",
            "options": [
                "A. Legislative Council",
                "B. Legislative Assembly",
                "C. Governor‟s Office",
                "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Legislative Council"
        },
        {
            "question": "In any State of India, Legislative Council can be created or can be abolished by",
            "options": [
                "A. The President on the recommendation of the Governor of the State",
                "B. The Parliament",
                "C. The Parliament as per Resolution passed by the Legislative Assembly of the State",
                "D. The Governor on the recommendation of the Council of Ministers"
            ],
            "answer": "C. The Parliament as per Resolution passed by the Legislative Assembly of the State"
        },
        {
            "question": "The provisions for creation and abolition of Legislative Councils in any State is included in Indian Constitution under",
            "options": [
                "A. Article 170",
                "B. Article 169",
                "C. Article 168",
                "D. Article 167"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Article 169"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who conducts the State Assembly Elections?",
            "options": [
                "A. Chief Justice of High Court",
                "B. State Election Commission",
                "C. Election Commission of India",
                "D. Governor of the State"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Election Commission of India"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who among the following is the final authority to decide any question relating to disqualification of a Member of a House of Legislature of a State?",
            "options": [
                "A. Governor",
                "B. Speaker of the Legislative Assembly",
                "C. Chief Minister",
                "D. High Court"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Governor"
        },
        {
            "question": "The „Contingency Fund‟ of the State is operated by",
            "options": [
                "A. The Governor of the State",
                "B. The Chief Minister of the State",
                "C. The State Finance Minister",
                "D. State Legislature"
            ],
            "answer": "D. State Legislature"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the head of the government of the state?",
            "options": [
                "A. Chief Minister",
                "B. Governor",
                "C. President",
                "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Chief Minister"
        },
        {
            "question": "A person who is not a member of the state legislature can be appointed Chief Minister for how many months?",
            "options": [
                "A. 2 months",
                "B. 3 months",
                "C. 4 months",
                "D. 6 months"
            ],
            "answer": "D. 6 months"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who administers the oath of Chief Minister?",
            "options": [
                "A. President",
                "B. Governor",
                "C. Chief Justice of India",
                "D. Chief Justice of concerned High Court"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Governor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following statements about the Chief Minister of a State is NOT CORRECT?",
            "options": [
                "A. The Chief Minister is appointed by the Governor",
                "B. The Chief Minister generally presides over the Cabinet Meetings",
                "C. The Governor has to exercise all his functions on the advice of the Chief Minister",
                "D. Ministers are appointed by the Governor on the advice of the Chief Minister"
            ],
            "answer": "C. The Governor has to exercise all his functions on the advice of the Chief Minister"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term of Chief Minister of a state?",
            "options": [
                "A. 3 years",
                "B. 5 years",
                "C. 6 years",
                "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. None of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who among the following popular personalities was never a Chief Minister of Independent Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "B. Sir Muhammad Sadulla",
                "C. Aishnurarn Medhi",
                "D. Airnala Prasad Chaliha"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Sir Muhammad Sadulla"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1973 the capital of Assam shifted from Shillong to Dispur, Who was the Chief Minister of Assam at that time?",
            "options": [
                "A. Sarat Chandra Singha",
                "B. Prafulla Mahanta",
                "C. Golap Baruha",
                "D. Bimala Prashad Chaliha"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Sarat Chandra Singha"
        }
    ]
}
